Finding Aid for the Ralph D. Cornell Papers LSC.1411
UCLA Library Special Collections
Ralph D. Cornell papers
1925-1972
UCLA Library Special Collections
Cornell, Ralph D, 1890-1972
LSC.1411
56.0 Linear Feet (80 boxes, 16 cartons, 56 oversize boxes, and 23 oversize folders)
Ralph D. Cornell was the supervising landscape architect at UCLA from 1937-72. Some of Cornell's other landscape architecture projects included Pomona College, Torrey Pines Park, Los Angeles Music Center, and La Brea Tar Pits. The collection consists of office files, business records, correspondence, photographs, slides, glass negatives, and books related to Ralph D. Cornell's career as a landscape architect and designer.
Restrictions on Access
Open for research. All requests to access special collections materials must be made in advance using the request button located on this page.
Provenance/Source of Acquisition
Vera Barnes Cornell, bequest, 1992.
UCLA Catalog Record ID
UCLA Catalog Record ID: 999645373606533
Biography
Ralph D. Cornell was born in Holdrege, New England; his family moved to Long Beach, California, in 1908; attended Pomona College, California and Harvard Graduate School of Landscape Architecture; enlisted in U.S. Armed Forces during World War I; supervising landscape architect, UCLA, 1937-72; some of Cornell's other landscape architecture projects included Pomona College, Torrey Pines Park, Los Angeles Music Center, and La Brea Tar Pits; died on April 6, 1972.
Scope and Content
Collection consists of office files, business records, correspondence, photographs, slides, glass negatives, and books related to the career of landscape architect and designer Ralph D. Cornell.
Related Material
Half a Century as a Southern California Landscape Architect [oral history transcript] / Ralph D. Cornell, interviewee. UCLA Oral History Department interview, 1970. Available at Department of Special Collections, UCLA.
Existence and Location of Copies
Digital reproductions of materials from the Ralph D. Cornell papers are available electronically at https://digital2.library.ucla.edu/viewItem.do?ark=21198/zz0008c7sv
Photographs.; Gardens -- California, Southern -- Design.; Landscape architects -- California, Southern -- Archives.; University of California, Los Angeles -- History; Cornell, Ralph D.--Archives.
- Projects--photographs. (Box 1)
- Ralph D. Cornell library--General interest. (Box 2-4, 7)
- Ralph D. Cornell library--General interest and professional interest. (Box 5, Box 6)
- Ralph D. Cornell library--Professional interest. (Box 8, Box 9)
- Ralph D. Cornell library--Horticultural journals and general interest. (Box 10)
- Ralph D. Cornell library--Horticultural journals. (Box 11)
- Ralph D. Cornell library--Professional interest. (Box 12, Box 13, Box 14, Box 15, Box 16, Box 17)
- Slides--sleeves 1-72. (Box 18)
- Slides--sleeves 73-144. (Box 19)
- Slides--sleeves 145-216. (Box 20)
- Slides--sleeves 217-288. (Box 21)
- Slides--sleeves 289-360. (Box 22)
- Slides--sleeves 361-432. (Box 23)
- Slides--sleeves 433-452. (Box 24)
- Personal & family. (Box 25-31, 35, 53)
- Personal financial records. (Box 32, Box 33, Box 34)
- Speeches, lectures, classes by Ralph D. Cornell. (Box 36, Box 37)
- Writings by Ralph D. Cornell. (Box 38)
- Published articles & photos by Ralph D. Cornell. (Box 39-48, 57)
- Publishers' correspondence. (Box 49-50, 52)
- Issues of Lasca Leaves. (Box 51)
- Plaques, printing plate (oak tree). (Box 54)
- Conspicuous California Plants. (Box 55)
- Personal financial records. (Box 56)
- Design files. (Box 58, Box 59, Box 60, Box 61, Box 62)
- Design files--landscape architecture subject index & plant material index. (Box 63)
- Office files--early & Cook, Hall & Cornell. (Box 64)
- Office receipts & miscellaneous business correspondence. (Box 65)
- Business correspondence & job records. (Box 66)
- Job records. (Box 67, Box 68, Box 69)
- Job records & office files. (Box 70)
- Office files. (Box 71, Box 72, Box 73, Box 74)
- Partnership records & job records. (Box 75)
- Pomona. (Box 76, Box 77, Box 78)
- UCLA. (Box 79, Box 80)
- Professional associations. (Box 81)
- Business address files. (Box 82)
- Theodore Payne. (Box 83)
- Plans & sketches. (Box 84)
- Photographs. (Box 85)
- Sketches, drawings & material collected by Ralph D. Cornell. (Box 86)
- Sketches, drawings, certificates. (Box 87)
- Plans. (Box 88)
- Job records. (Box 89)
- Office files--cash & checking records., 1957-1967 (Box 90)
- Plaques & printing plates. (Box 91)
- Miscellaneous files. (Box 92-98, 104)
- Personal--postcards from World War I. (Box 99)
- Issues of Mastekey. (Box 100)
- Photographs--scenic views, figure studies. (Box 101)
- Photographs--Hawaii. (Box 102)
- Photographs--Europe & Central America. (Box 103)
- Photographs--including flowerscapes by Ralph D. Cornell. (Box 105)
- Color negatives (4 × 5) identified by types of plants. (Box 106)
- Photos of plants by Ralph D. Cornell (A-C). (Box 107)
- Photos of plants by Ralph D. Cornell (D-N). (Box 108)
- Photos of plants by Ralph D. Cornell (O-Z). (Box 109)
- Daniel Webster box. (Box 110)
- Photos by Ralph D. Cornell & photos by J.W. Garrison. (Box 111)
- Jobs--photos & negatives. World War II. (Box 112)
- Jobs--individual photos. (Box 113)
- Prints & negatives--Monument Valley, Utah, New Mexico, Arizona, California. (Box 114)
- Prints & negatives--Hawaii, plants, Jamaica, UCLA. (Box 115)
- Color negatives--mostly trees. (Box 116)
- Ralph D. Cornell photo index of architecture & plant materials., 1912-1920 (Box 117)
- Glass slides. (Box 118, Box 119, Box 120)
- Black & white prints and negatives--exotic trees, eucalyptus and pines. (Box 121)
- Black & white prints and negatives--exotic trees A-ES. (Box 122)
- Black & white prints and negatives--Exotic trees--Pinus-street trees. (Box 123)
- Black & white prints and negatives--Birds, animals, plants, trees, arboretum, miscellaneous and color transparencies. (Box 124)
- Black & white prints and negatives--trees--California & Western natives. (Box 125)
- Black & white prints and negatives--California native shrubs. (Box 126)
- Black & white prints and negatives--desert plants & California wildflowers. (Box 127)
- Black & white prints and negatives--succulents, agaves, aloes, & bromeliads. (Box 128)
- Black & white prints and negatives--palms. (Box 129)
- Black & white prints and negatives--California wildflowers, aloes & succulents. (Box 130)
- Black & white prints and negatives--Shrubs, exotics, vines & protaceae. (Box 131)
- Black & white prints and negatives--Fungi, flowering plants & exotic miscellaneous plants. (Box 132)
- Black & white prints and negatives--Vines--ground covers. (Box 133)
- Color transparencies--Rosa bansksiae, protaceae, miscellaneous. (Box 134)
- Color transparencies--Trees & echiums. (Box 135)
- Color transparencies--miscellaneous plants. (Box 136)
- Color transparencies--Palms, bromeliads, cactus, California missions, Santa Fe gardens, miscellaneous. (Box 137)
- Color transparencies--desert plants, wildflower book, Theodore Payne, cactus. (Box 138)
- Color transparencies and black & white prints and negatives--Huntington Gardens, Baja & Mexico, miscellaneous plants. (Box 139)
- Color transparencies--miscellaneous plants, UCLA, Rose Hills. (Box 140)
- Color transparencies--vines, xerophytes, yuccas. (Box 141)
- Color transparencies--Shrubs (exotics), shrubs (native), agaves. (Box 142)
- Color transparencies--Wildflowers, exotics & street trees. (Box 143)
- Color transparencies--Hawaii, succulents, palms, ground cover, exotic plants, protaceae, vines. (Box 144)
- Color transparencies--Scenery, miscellaneous and Southwest scenes. (Box 145)
- Color transparencies--Aloes, bromeliads, cactus, ferns, LASCA, portraits. (Box 146)
- Personal effects and camera equipment. (Box 147, Box 148, Box 149)
- Lloyd S. Whaley Garden--Plans,. (5)., 1949 (Box 150)
- Palomares Park, Pomona, California--Plans,. (2)., 1957 (Box 151)
- Centinela Park, Los Angeles, California--Plans. (5). (Box 152)
- Redondo Beach Park, California--Plans,. (3)., 1947 (Box 153)
- Culver City Recreation Park, California--Plans, (3)., 1940 (Box 154)
- Palm Springs Field Club--Plans., 4 items. (Box 155)
- Oak Park Cemetary, Claremont, California--Plans., 9 items. (Box 156)
- North American Aid Recreation Park, Inglewood, California--Plans., 4 items. (Box 157)
- City of Upland Park--Plans,., 1936; 2 items. (Box 158)
- China Garden Tract--Plans,., 1927; 3 items. (Box 159)
- Chula Vista Tract--Plans,., 1927; 1 item [In same folder with China Garden Tract]. (Box 159)
- Oak Park Cemetary, Claremont Colleges--Plans., 9 items. (Box 160)
- American Potash and Chemical Corporation. Trona, California--Plans,., 1942; 16 items. (Box 161)
- National Orange Show--Plans,., 1938; 9 items. (Box 162)
- National Orange Show--Plans,., 1939-1941; 10 items. (Box 163)
- National Orange Show--Plans,., 1948; 9 items. (Box 164)
- National Orange Show--Plans,., 1949; 4 items. (Box 165)
- National Orange Show--Plans,., 1950; 5 items. (Box 166)
- National Orange Show--Plans,., 1951-1955; 7 items. (Box 167)
- National Orange Show--Plans,., 1956; 8 items. (Box 168)
- National Orange Show--Plans, n.d.; 7 items. (Box 169)
- Renderings., 3 items. (Box 170)
- Art work. (Box 171)
- Triptych screen [damaged]. (Box 172)
- Renderings. (Box 173)
- Miscellaneous plans and proof sheets. (Box 174)
- Miscellaneous plans. (Box 175)
- Southgate Recreation Park,., 1946; 2 items. (Box 176)
- China Garden Tract. Claremont, California,., 1928; 1 item. (Box 176)
- Hillside Memorial Park,., 1945; 9 items. (Box 176)
- Hollywood Boulevard survey., 2 items [damaged]. (Box 176)
- Chula Vista Tract,., August 1927 (Box 177)
- Sketch plan of Rancho Joaquina. Phoenix, Arizona,., January 1925 (Box 177)
- General plan for a recreation park. Upland California,., July 1936 (Box 177)
- Glen Haven Memorial Park. Los Angeles, California, n.d. (Box 177)
- Preliminary site development plan for University Elementary School,., June 1947 (Box 177)